Guide to the Robert R. Wilson papers, 1936-2000.
Wilson, Robert R. papers, 1936-2000.
- Series IX. Professional miscellany
  - Memorabilia
    - NOBE: desk plaque, 1971 (Box 12)
    - Medal: Akademiia Hauk SSSR Bicentennial, 1974 (Box 12)
    - Medal: Ob'edinenyi Institut Iadernykh Issledovanii, 1976 (Box 12)
    - Cornell 10 GeV Synchrotron/ 25th Anniversary/ November 1992: 2 pieces of metal, 1992 (Box 12)
    - Unmarked, twisted piece of copper, n.d. (Box 12)
  - Audio Cassettes
    - Memorial Service, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Student Days, n.d.; tr-7880a - tr-7882a
    - Jane interview, n.d.; tr-7883a
    - Starting College/Student Days, 1988; tr7884a
- Series X. Personal/family
  - Obituaries
    - 6 photocopies, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Memorial Service announcement and bulletin, 4/28/2000 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence
    - Family, 1937-1993 (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Personal, 1946-1995 (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Personal: no surname, not identified, miscellaneous, 1965-1987 (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - R. R. W.'s and Jane's 50th anniversary, 9/2/1990 (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - R. R. W.'s 80th birthday, 5/7/1994 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Genealogy
    - Notes, charts, research (Box 11, Folder 30)
    - Old family letters (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Legal Documents
    - Brand certificate, change of beneficiary, certificat de domicile, will, correspondence re wills and deeds, settlement of will, lease, 1922-1992 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Career/Employment
    - UCB: student and professor, 1935-1953 (Box 11, Folder 33)
    - Princeton, 1940-1965 (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Los Alamos, 1944-1965 (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Harvard, 1945-1990 (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Cornell University, 1951-1966 (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - University of Washington, Summer 1951, 1951-1984 (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - École Normale Superieure, 1954-1955 (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - NSF, 1956-1987 (Box 11, Folder 40)
    - General Atomic, 1957-1961 (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - General Electric, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - BBC: film, 1965 (Box 11, Folder 43)
    - Alfred P. Sloan Foundation: book, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Columbia University, 1980 (Box 11, Folder 45)
    - University of California, Davis, 1982-1986 (Box 11, Folder 46)
    - Medical Accelerator Corporation, 1985-1986 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Scholarships
    - Applications, correspondence, 1954-1961 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Consultancy/Guest Speaker/Committee Member
    - Offers, correspondence, reimbursal information, 1951-1992 (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - Employment offers
    - Correspondence, 1944-1988 (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - Financial matters
    - Sculpture expenses and earnings, royalties, 1981-1995 (Box 11, Folder 51)
    - Contributions and thank you letters, 1954-1990 (Box 11, Folder 52)
    - Check stub, bank form letter, 1954-1987 (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - Poetry
    - Personal: poetry, 1983-1992 (Box 11, Folder 54)
  - Sketches
    - Personal: sketches, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 55)
    - Personal: plot maps and building plans for residence in Tesuque, N. M., 1966-1988 (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Personal: building plans for residence in Tesuque, N. M, 1987-1988 (Folder 5)
  - Health
    - Personal: health, 1993-1996 (Box 11, Folder 56)
  - Automobiles
    - Personal: automobiles, 1937-1981 (Box 11, Folder 57)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Personal: renewal forms, fingerprint cards, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 58)
    - Personal: notes, 1985-1996 (Box 11, Folder 59)
  - Residences
    - Personal: Ventura, California house, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 60)
    - Personal: Tesuque, New Mexico house, 1968-1983 (Box 11, Folder 61)
    - Personal: Tesuque, New Mexico house, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 62)
    - Personal: Tesuque, New Mexico house, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 63)
    - Personal: Tesuque, New Mexico house, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 64)
    - Personal: Tesuque, New Mexico house, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 65)
    - Personal: Tesuque, New Mexico house, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 66)
    - Personal: "Valhalla" (Florida) house, 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 67)
- Series XI. Visual images
  - Photographs
    - Architectural models, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 68)
    - Argonne National Laboratory, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 69)
    - Art: Sculptures, 1967-1987 (Box 11, Folder 70)
    - Oppenheimer Memorial -- Princeton University, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 71)
    - Cornell University synchrotron, 1954-1978 (Box 11, Folder 72-74)
    - Dubnah plot, 8/28/1963 (Box 11, Folder 75)
    - Fermilab, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 76-78)
    - Fermilab: Weston, Illinois site, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 18)
    - Harvard University: Paul H. Donaldson Cruft Laboratory, 1947-1948 (Box 11, Folder 79)
    - Harvard University: Science Center, 1996 (Box 11, Folder 80)
    - I. U. P. U. I., n.d. (Box 11, Folder 81)
    - Ithaca Falls, 1927 (Box 11, Folder 82)
    - Jerusalem: cyclotron, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 83)
    - Los Alamos: Ground Zero, Trinity, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 84)
    - Los Alamos: X-Building Lab equipment, [1944] (Box 11, Folder 85-86)
    - (Los Alamos): aerial view, n.d. (Folder 5)
    - Mittenwald, 10/1956 (Box 11, Folder 87)
    - New Delhi, 1997 (Box 11, Folder 88)
    - Paris: Mesotron Project, [1954] (Box 11, Folder 89)
    - People: R.R.W., 1960-2000 (Box 11, Folder 90)
    - People: H. Anderson, D. Froman, E. Fermi, H. Barschal, R.R.W., J. Fowler, J. Manley, S. Neddermeyer, R. King, E. Bretscher, E. Segre, H. Staub, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 91)
    - People: R.R.W. and Boyce McDaniel, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 91)
    - People: Romagnosi, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 92)
    - People: Dave Sloan, Bob Cornog, Martin Kamen, Wilfred Mann, Oppenheimer, Mr. Vig, Dave Kalffeld, Wynn Salsbury, John Backus, Langsdorf, Joe Hamilton, Sam Simmons, Ed McMillan, R.R.W., Bill Brobeck, Ernie Lyman, Jack Livingood, John Lawrence, Robt Serber, Paul Aebersold, Franz Kurie, Prof. Birge, EOL, Don Cooksey, Art Snell, Louis Alvarez, Phil Abelan (framed image), [1942-1945] (Box 11, Folder 93)
    - People: Hans Bethe and Boyce McDaniel, 1968 (Box 11, Folder 94)
    - People: Fermilab Staff, 2000 (Box 11, Folder 94)
    - People: Professor John W. DeWire, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 94)
    - People: meeting at Brookhaven National Laboratory, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 95)
    - Tokoharu University synchrotron under construction, 1952 (Box 11, Folder 96)
    - Tokoharu University Synchrotron light beam, 1956 (Box 11, Folder 96)
    - UCB model, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 97)
    - Yan Yong-Sheng models, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 98)
    - Miscellany: page of Irene Curie's notes, 1954 (Box 11, Folder 99)
    - Miscellany: Romeo and Juliet (ballet), Moscow (postcard), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 99)
    - Miscellany unidentified, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 100)
    - Personal: house in Tesuque, New Mexico, 1965-1993 (Box 11, Folder 101-102)
  - Transparencies
    - Unidentified, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 103)
  - Negatives
    - Beta [paper], 1958 (Box 11, Folder 104)
    - Fermilab, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 104)
    - Figure [f/(k/E) plot], n.d. (Box 11, Folder 104)
    - 1 Gev Synch[rotron], [1954] (Box 11, Folder 105)
    - Monte Carlo showers, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 105)
    - Wilson synchrotrons: machinery, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 105)
    - Wilson synchrotrons: figures, data plots, plans, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 105)
    - House and land in Tesuque, New Mexico, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 106)
  - Slides
    - DUSAF: scientific objects, 1969-1989 (Box 11, Folder 107)
    - Cornell: LNS, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 108)
    - Fermilab, 1969-1992 (Box 11, Folder 109)
    - 50th (wedding) anniversary party, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 110)
    - Sculpture, 1974-1977 (Box 11, Folder 111)
    - Unidentified: machinery (made in West Germany), n.d. (Box 11, Folder 112)
  - Video
    - Robert Wilson: A Life of Courage and Creativity, 5838 (Box 17)
- Series XII. Miscellany
  - Memorabilia
    - Boy Citizens of America/Camp Tosebo: button and medal, n.d. (Box 12)
- Series XIII. Personnel (RESTRICTED)
  - General Personnel
    - Columbia University, 1981 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Cornell University: Salary and appointment letters, 1947-1950 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Cornell University: Staff Rosters, 1948-1967 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Cornell University: General Division memos and information, 1947-1964 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Cornell University: Budgets (individual salaries indicated), 1951-1967 (Box 15, Folder 5-8)
    - Cornell University: Grades, Course Rosters, 1951-1960 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Harvard University, 1946-1947 (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Los Alamos, 1944-1945 (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Princeton University, 1942-1943 (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - University of California, Berkeley: Course Roster, [1930]-1932 (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - University of Chicago: Grades, 1980 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - University of Washington (State), 1984 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Individuals: letters of reference, inquiries about employment, etc.
    - A-Z by name of subject of correspondence, 1933-1992 (Box 15, Folder 16-38)
    - A (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - B (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - C (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - D (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - E (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - F (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - G (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - H (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - J (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - K (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - L (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - M-McCusker (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - McDaniel-Muller (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - N (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - O (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - P (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Q (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - R (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - S (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - T (Box 15, Folder 35)
    - V (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - W (Box 15, Folder 37)
    - Y-Z (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - Acosta, Julius Caesar C., Quezon City, Philippines, to R.R.W., Ithaca, NY, re science and religion [tls], 7/10/1996 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Carter, Lucius, Cartech, Inc., to R.R.W., re sculpture [pls], enclosures: Charles Perry sculptures in Tampa [phc] (enclosure only), 8/22/1986 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Hayakawa, Satio, University of Delhi, to R.R.W., C. U., re visit to Japan, experimental results [tls], P.S. [al], 10/18/1951 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - McMillan, Priscilla, to "Dear Wilsons," re Sudoplatov scandal [als], 4 clippings [phc], 5/4/1994 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Moon, Philip, University of Birmingham, to R.R.W., re upcoming conference [tm]; reply, 6/19/1953 [cc], n.d. (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Philip, Fayetta Harris, Sacramento, to "Dear Friends," re origin of electrons and atomic energy [mc], 1945 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Shank, W. Bradford, to "Those Interested," re proposed magazine [mc], 9/14/1945 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Singer, Daniel M., FAS, to R.R.W., C. U., re Oppenheimer Fermi Award program, requests copy of State Department's China letter [tls], program [phc] (enclosures only), 12/3/1963 (Box 16, Folder 8)
    - Stratton, F. J. M., Society for Visiting Scientists, Ltd.: notice to oversea members [mc], agenda [mc], 6/1950 (Box 16, Folder 9)
    - Physics Today article, "A World organization for the future of high-energy physics [phc], 1964 (Box 16, Folder 10)
    - Linear Accelerator, 1948 (Box 16, Folder 11)
    - Los Alamos, 1943-1983 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - American Association of Scientific Workers, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - ALAS: atomics, 1945-1984 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - A.S.A.E., 1948 (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Association of Scientists of Cornell University, 1949 (Box 16, Folder 16)
    - Atomic threat, 1947, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - NCAI, 1947 (Box 16, Folder 18)